Russell Pitre

Senior Software Engineer

Personal Info

Address 3 Pine Edge Way Hatfield, MA 01038

Phone <u>617.834.2644</u>

Email <u>rpitre@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/russell-pitre/

Education

WentWorth Institute of Technology Computer Engineering Technology 1996-2000

Amazon Web Services

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

2121-Present

Skills



Summary

Russell Pitre is a seasoned professional software developer with over 20 years experience developing, delivering, and maintaining effective business applications in the construction, environmental, and financial industries. Russell's specialties are working with business experts to design technical solutions to meet the needs of the business. He has a sense of urgency, is detailed oriented, understands the meaning of client satisfaction, is self-directed and excels at working on his own or as part of a team. He has a deep seeded commitment for the long-term success of the organization he works for and enjoys working with others to accomplish the financial and cultural goals of the organization. He is willing and able to learn new technologies quickly and effectively, is well read and is up to date with current software industry trends.

Work History

CoreLogic (formerly Roostify, Inc.)

Remote, US

2022-present Digital Mortgage Platform

Worked as a Senior Software Engineer designing and developing third-party integrations for the Digital Mortgage Platform SASS product. Led the design and development of the user interface framework enabling customers to fully customize the mortgage loan application experience.

Skills: Java, Spring Boot, Microservices, TDD, BDD, Kubernetes, React, TypeScript, DevOps

Cognizant Softvision

Remote, US

2021-2022 **Discover Financial, Inc.**

Worked as a Senior Developer Coach to "skill-up" the software developers on the Credit Operations team by pairing up to demonstrate best coding practices while using the TDD methodology.

Skills: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, RabbitMQ, React, TDD, BDD

Windsor Solutions, Inc.

Northampton, MA

2019-2021 **nFORM**

Contributed to the design and development of numerous features to nFORM. nFORM is a system that streamlines the process of permitting, licensing, and certification for the regulated environmental community.

Skills: C#, React, .NET Core, SQL Server

2019-2021 Windsor UI-Kit

Designed and developed from the ground up a user interface component library built on React and EmotionJS. The component library is used by various products at Windsor Solutions.

Skills: React, Emotion, Styled Components, Storybook, Webpack

2018-2021 BeachGuard Management System

Ohio Department of Health

Designed and developed both the public and administrative portions of a mobile ready web-based system for managing the healthy beaches in the state of Ohio.

Skills: React, .NET Core, REST Services

2018-2021 **nSITE Explorer**

Designed and developed a mobile ready web-based GIS solution to search and view environmental interest data on a map. nSITE is part of Windsor's integrated environmental data management suite, nVIRO. The nSITE Explorer app has many features including the ability to draw and measure features on the map, search by a variety of data attributes, and others.

Skills: Open Layers, React, .NET Core, SQL Server

2017-2021 nSPECT Mobile

Integral development team member of an Android and iOS mobile application designed to work as an offline mobile inspections tool. The nSPECT mobile application is available on both Google Play Store and the Apple App Store.

Skills: React Native, React, redux, iOS, Android

2016-2017 Solid Waste Division – Recycle Database Management

King County Department of Natural Resources and Parks

Assisted in the development of modernizing the solid waste website to work with current technologies. One of the main areas of focus was making the site mobile friendly.

Skills: SQL Server, C#, jQuery, KnockoutJS, Bootstrap

2014-2015 Underground Storage Tank System

Massachusetts Department of Environmental Protection

Assisted in the development of a web-based system for tracking underground storage tanks.

Skills: Java, Tomcat Application Server, Spring Framework, Hibernate, Apache Wicket

2012-2014 Pesticides System

New York Department of Environmental Conservation

Integral development team member of a multi-phase implementation of a web-based system for managing the pesticides program.

Skills: Java, Tomcat Application Server, Spring Framework, Hibernate, Apache Wicket

2011-2012

Routine Emissions Reporting System New Mexico Environment Department

Assisted in the development of a web-based routine emissions reporting system.

Skills: Oracle, Java, Tomcat Application Server, Spring Framework, Hibernate, Apache Wicket

Shawmut Design and Construction

Boston, MA

2009-2011 ADP HRIS Integration

Designed and implemented an integration process to synchronize employee information with a third party payroll processing system feeding all internal downstream enterprise systems.

Skills: Java, Spring Framework, Apache Camel, SQL Server, Quartz Scheduler

2005-2011 Corporate Intranet

Designed, developed, and implemented the Shawmut Intranet, a core business application used by all Shawmut staff. The Intranet was built from the ground up to serve as an extensible foundation in which to build transactional business applications. The layered based architecture reduces total cost of ownership by promoting high code quality, maintainability and enabling rapid application development. The user interface was designed to have a consistent look and feel, easy to use navigation features, and other impressive UI features.

Skills: Java, Spring Framework, SQL Server, Hibernate, JSP